Hello friends, welcome again to a new video.
Friends, in today's
video we are going to tell you how to
renew Maruti Suzuki car insurance.
Yes friends, if you
have any vehicle, any insurance for your vehicle
or any
policy, it is about to expire.  And
friends, you do not have time to
go to the agency or renew it through the company.
So friends,
in this situation you can renew your insurance policy sitting at home.
So now friends,
you do not need to go to the company to renew your car policy.  You do
n't need to go to the agency.  You can renew
your car policy from your mobile phone while sitting at home.
In this video, we are going to teach you
how you can renew your car policy sitting at home.
Friends,
whatever policy you have for your vehicle, whatever
insurance you have, whether it is your third party
insurance or your zero type
insurance, any policy,
you can renew it very easily sitting at home.
So let me start with the video, friends.
How will you be
able to renew your policy?  Step by step
I am going to show you the entire procedure live.
So you have to stay tuned to the video.   Do
not skip the video.  So
friends, let's start the video.
Friends, before starting the video
I would like to make just one request to you.
If you have come to my channel for the first time then
please subscribe to my channel.
Also, you have to press the bell icon
so that
you can get the notification of our next video on your mobile
phone.  So let's get started.
What do you have to do first?  You have to open
Google Chrome browser in your mobile phone.
And
friends, here you have to type
Maruti Suzuki Insurance in the search bar.  So
let me type it here.  As
friends you can see here
I have typed Maruti Suzuki Insurance here.
After that you have to click on the search bar.
Friends, what do you have to do after clicking
?  You have to come a little to the lower side.
Friends, you will get
to see many websites here.  But
you have to click on only one website.
You have to scroll down and
come to the bottom side.  Friends,
as soon as you come to the bottom side, you will
see a website here.  This one
as you can see here Maruti
Suzuki Insurance Simple you have to
click here.  Let me click here.
So after clicking, the dashboard of the
official website of Maruti Suzuki Insurance will
open in front of you like this.  Now friends,
you can also enter the policy number of the policy which you want to renew here.
Otherwise, if you have the registration number of your vehicle,
you can enter that also.
So friends, I
enter the registration number of my vehicle here.
But we have entered the registration number of our vehicle.
Friends, after entering, what do you have to do now?  We have to
renew our policy.
To renew is simple, you can see
a renewal option here.  Simply you have to
click here.  Come on guys, let me
click here.  Friends,
before clicking, you can see here whether you have taken any claim in the last
policy i.e. your last policy
or not
, you can say yes or no from here.
So, I have not taken any claim.
From here we click on No.
Friends, after clicking on No, now you
can see the renew option here.  Simply
you have to click here.  Let me
click here.
After clicking, you have to enter the mobile number which is registered in your policy
here.
What do you have to do after entering?  You have to receive an OTP on the same mobile number.
So first of all we
enter our mobile number here.
Here we have entered the mobile number.
After entering the mobile number,
you can see here Send OTP, simply
click here.  Now friends,
after clicking, a four digit OTP would have come on your mobile number.
You have to enter the OTP here.
After entering the OTP, a page like this will
open in front of you and friends,
here you will get to see your name which will be
seen in the shortcut and
friends, here you will get to see from which company your policy is
running.
Now friends, what do you have to do?
You have to renew your policy i.e. you have to
renew it.  For that you have to first
click OK from here.  After clicking OK,
friends, all your details in your policy can be
seen from here.
You can see your date of
birth here.  Your PAN number can be
seen.  And friends,
whatever your address is, it becomes visible.
Here you can see that by scrolling down a little you can
see your PIN code.
Your city gets to be seen.
Now friends, what do you have to do?  First of all,
you have to check here that
if your email ID is in an email ID
then you have to leave it as it is.  Guys, what should you do if
you don't see your email ID here
?  First of all, you have to
enter your email ID here so that
whenever our policy is renewed,
you can get its PDF file very easily.
So first of all we
enter our email ID here.   You have
entered your email ID.
After entering the email ID, you have to
come to the bottom side.  Friends, after coming to the bottom side,
if your PIN code is correct here then
you have to leave it.  Otherwise you
can also change your PIN code from here.
Now you can see the locality here.
Simply you have to click here.
Friends, what do you have to do after clicking
?  You have to select the area in which you live.  That means
you have to select the
city in which you live, that is, the district which you feel is yours.
So I
select my district from here.
Friends, after selecting the district,
you have to enter your city here.  If you
live in a city, I will
type my city from here.  Friends,
my city has been typed here.  Now
friends, what do you have to do?  You have to come
down a little bit, friends.  After coming down,
as you can see here, all the
complete details of your vehicle are available here.
What is your vehicle number?  And
friends, you can see the engine number, chassis number of your vehicle
here.
You have to come down a little bit and
here you can see a continue option.
Simply you have to click here.  Let
me click here.  Now friends,
after clicking, a new page will
open in front of us again.  What do you have to do on this page
?  You have to come a little to the lower side.
Friends, as you
come to the bottom side, here you can
see whatever policy you have for your car.
So, as you can see here, the
policy that is currently in place on our vehicle.
So, as you can see here, one of
our policies is
showing us till July 1, 2026.  That means it will be done by
2026 after our renewal.
You can see that our second policy is
valid till 23 March 2026.
While scrolling down, you have to come a little to the bottom
side.  Friends, as soon as you
come to the bottom side, here you get
to see the details of your nominee.  So
if you want to make any correction in your nominee's details,
you can do it.
Otherwise you can leave it.  Again
you have to come a little bit downwards.
You can watch it here.
Whatever is the amount for renewal of your policy,
you can see it here.  You can see here
which company you want to renew your policy from.
You have to come to the bottom side.  You can do it as per your convenience
from whichever company you want to renew your policy.
Whatever amount is there here, the same amount is coming to everyone.
So, you can choose the company as per your choice.  You have to
come to the bottom side.  You
can see other insurance companies here.
So if you do not choose any of these companies
then you
can also choose any other company.  After clicking here,
after clicking here, as you
can see here, some more companies have been
displayed here in front of us.  As you
can see here, United Company has also
come to us.  Friends, before this
our policy of United Company is
running well.  So friends, what do we have to do now
?  This policy has to be renewed from United Company only.
So let me click here.
Now friends, after clicking, all the
complete details of your policy can be
seen here.  Now
friends, what you have to do is to
renew the policy, you can see
a continue option here.  Simply you have to
click here.  Come on guys, let me
click here.  Friends, after clicking,
a new page will open in front of you again.
Friends, after the page opens, you will be able to see the
total amount of your policy and how much you have to
pay.
₹4692 is the
total we have to pay here.  That means here
we also have to pay GST charge of ₹716.
Now friends, you have to scroll down and
reach the site below.
As you can see here, our
KYC has been verified online.
Complete details can be seen inside your policy.
Here you can see that the policy will
start.
You will find the expiry date of the policy here.
And friends, if you come below, you can
see your mobile number and your name.
Your email ID can also be seen.
Your address
is visible.  And friends, you get
to see your district.  What do you have to do now
?  You have to come a little to the lower side.
You can also check all the details of your vehicle.  As soon as you scroll down,
you have to come a little to the bottom
side again.  Here you can
see the details of your nominee also.
Whatever is the name of your nominee, it can be seen.
And friends, whatever the age of the nominee is, it gets
to be seen.  You have to
come to the bottom side.  And as you
can see what do you have to do here?  ₹4692 to be
paid online only.  What to do?
Here you can see a simple captcha,
you have to tick mark it here.  Friends,
what to do now after ticking?
We have to pay whatever amount is there for this policy.
To pay, you
can see the total premium here, simply you have to
click here.  So after clicking,
a new page will open in front of us again.
Now friends, what do we have to do on this page
?  Whatever policy we have,
whatever amount is there for that policy, it has to be paid online only.
To pay online you
can see here. You
can also make your payment through debit card.  And
friends, you can also pay your payment through net banking.
And friends,
if you use Google Pay PhonePe
then you can also make payment online through UPI here.
Friends,
here we choose for net banking.  So I
click on net banking.
Friends, after clicking,
you can select which bank's net banking you have.
Friends, I have SBI net
banking, so I click on SBI.
Friends, after clicking on SBI,
you will see an option here called
Pay Now.  Simply you have to click here.
Come on guys, let me click here.
After clicking,
it will take some process.  Something like this.  And
friends, after taking the process, as you
can see here, you have to enter your State Bank of
India user ID
here.  And friends,
whatever is your State Bank of India internet
banking password, you have to
enter it here.  Here we have
entered our user ID.  Whatever
our password is, we have entered it.
After entering, you can see a
login button here, you simply have to click here.
Come on guys, let me click here.
Now friends, after clicking,
as you can see here, a page like this will
open in front of you and here
you will be able to see your bank account
and friends, you can confirm from here how much amount is going to be debited from your account.
You will find the reference number
here.  Scroll down and
come to the bottom side.  And
friends, as you come to the bottom side,
you will see an option called
confirm.  Simply you have to
click on the confirm option.  Let me click here.
So after clicking on confirm,
you have to come to the bottom side again.
Here you get to see the bank account details.
Scroll down and
come to the bottom side.  Friends, as soon as
you come to the bottom side, an OTP would have come
on the mobile number linked to your bank account.
You have to enter the OTP here.
Here I have entered the OTP.
After entering the OTP,
you have to come to the bottom side again.  Here
you can see a confirm button.
Simply you have to click here.  Let
me click here.
After clicking, as you can see here,
our policy has been successfully renewed.  You
can see that the policy has been generated,
which means that our policy has been successfully
generated.  Now we
can also download this policy of ours.  Friends,
how do you want to download it?  As you
can see here, the policy number will be visible here
and the transaction ID number will be
visible here.  Friends, to
download the policy, you can see the
policy download option here.  Simply you have to
click here.  Come on guys, let me
click here.  After clicking,
as you can see here, your
policy has been successfully downloaded here.
Your PDF file
also comes in your Google Drive.  And friends, it
also appears in whatever gallery you have.
So let me show you here for
how many days our policy has been
renewed.  So let me
show you here that our policy has been renewed from 2 July 2025 i.e.
till 1 July 2026.
I have blurred the rest of the things
here for security purposes.
Now friends, in this way you
can renew your policy online sitting at home.
You don't need to go anywhere.   You
can renew your policy from home and download it within just 5 minutes.
So friends, if you
liked our video then please
like the video.  If you have
come to the channel for the first time then please subscribe to the channel.
To watch videos of similar content, you have to stay tuned to our channel.
So friends, I will meet you
next time on some good topic.
Ok bye till then.  Take care!  Thank
you